RAGUNATH.M.R

Bangalore India Phone: 9976901234. Email: raguus82@gmail.com

AFFILIATIONS:

A competent professional with 14+ years of experience in Behavioural Training, Leadership Process Operations, Customer Service.

Team Management, sales training, and experiential learning Events.

Proficient at managing training operations & experience of enhancing processes & service standards for business excellence.

Resourceful at maintaining cordial relations with client & providing value added customer service, ensuring quality and service norms to achieve the Platinum standard support.

Excellent interpersonal, communication and organisational skills with proven records of success in planning & execution.

Expert in process designing and implementation.

SKILLS:

Certified Six Sigma Green Belt from MSME.

Certified NLP (Neuro Linguistic Practitioner) from American Foundation of Neuro Linguistic Program.

Ability to support leaders overcome problems & increase performance through coaching. Adept at enabling behavioral changes through experiential insights.

Effective communication has helped harness business support & connect for training operations.

WORK HISTORY:

Dec 2018 - Till Date - Zonal Training Head - Zomato Media Pvt Ltd

Heading the training for South Zone(KA, TN and KL).

Heading the QC and BGV(Compliance) for PAN India.

Been able to reduce the QC fail(fake docs) from 54% to 2% in just 5months by designing and implementing new processes.

Been topping in PAN India on all training metrics for South since joining.

May 2017 - Nov 2018: Associate Vice President - Jana Small Finance Bank

Manage all the training requirement with a team of 5 trainer's.

Had been recognised as the best employee on turning around the collection with training intervention with a growth of 12 crore in collection process.

Had taken care of the Content designing on any requirement from business(Sales and Collection)

Had been one of the Key player among the entire training team PAN India.

Been an expert on creating and implementing process for the betterment of Sales and Collection.

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017: Training Manager – Indus Management Pvt Ltd | Chennai

Manage training for 3 States (TN, KA & KL) for Reliance JIO.

Specialist trainer for enterprise relationship managers on behavioural skills to handle HNI Customers.

Train new hires to perform cross-training exercises with experienced workers.

Review and assess training content for accuracy and policy compliance.

Jan 2012 – Feb 2017: Senior Trainer - Aircel Limited | Coimbatore

Delivered leadership & personal development program for mid-management leaders.

Specialist trainer for communication, cohesion building & need based behavioural interventions across the country.

Applied adult learning to address behavioural and capability issues impacting performance to enhance productivity.

Evaluated the effectiveness of functional training programs & ensure recommended process corrections to top management.

Conducted orientation sessions and organised on-the-job training for new hires.

Functional training execution for sales, marketing & customer service teams.

May 2011 - Jan 2012: Senior Consultant - Launchpad LLC | Coimbatore

Coordinated technical training and personality development classes for staff members. Developed surveys to identify training needs based on patterns & changes in students. Device alternative training methods if expected throughput were not reached for students Led daily, weekly and monthly coaching, counselling and feedback sessions.

June 2009 – April 2011: Senior Training Lead - Spanco BPO Services | Coimbatore

Execution of product & process training for Aircel process (prepaid & postpaid)

May 2006 – April 2008: **Trainer** – Sutherland Global Services | Chennai

Developed and managed communications strategies, plans and budgets.

Coached management on employee communication & clients on organisation changes.

Planned and launched innovative, creative and effective communications campaigns.

Upward feedback on brand consistency to the management.

May 2005 – April 2006: Customer Service Executive - Transworks | Bangalore

Accurately documented, researched & resolved customer service issues

Mastery of customer service management systems and databases.

Improved call centre functionality & service capacity through effective & timely resolution of customer complaints.

Defused volatile customer situations calmly and courteously.

Referred unresolved customer grievances to designated departments for further investigation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts from St. Aloysius International University, Bangalore. Diploma in Instrumentation Control Engineering (3 Years) VLB Janakiammal Polytechnic College, Anna University, Coimbatore

CERTIFICATION

Green belt certification in Six Sigma with MSME (Govt. Of India). Certified NLP Practitioner from American Foundation of NeuroLinguistic Program.

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Date Of Birth :10th Nov'82 Marital Status: :Married Blood Group: :'O' Positive Alternate Phone No. : 70103 60622